<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>adhd on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</title>
    <link>https://channikhabra.com/tags/adhd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in adhd on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:36:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://channikhabra.com/tags/adhd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping others to help myself</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-help-others-to-help-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:36:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-help-others-to-help-yourself/</guid>
      <description>It is near impossible for me to get something done if I don&amp;rsquo;t have 100% peaked interest in it at this very moment. Occasionally I can hyper focus on things, but that hyper focus rarely finish things. Hyper focus is like eating all the desert, leaving behind a plate full of broccoli.
I have noticed however that most of the times when I have actually finished something, I was, in my mind, helping someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Chaos : Org mode as a TODO list</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/managing-chaos-org-mode-as-a-todo-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/managing-chaos-org-mode-as-a-todo-list/</guid>
      <description>I am thinking about doing a small series of posts on how I am managing the chaos that I am trying to stop fighting. I hope the chaos of an ADHD mind can be utilized rather than fought against. So far it has been working out pretty great (for past ~8 months). This post is about how I manage my ever exploding list of things I want to do.
I believe one of the most important things is to externalize your thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to terms with ADHD - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 13:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-part-2/</guid>
      <description>One of the important aspects of living with ADHD is getting overwhelmed by thoughts. This is usually a major pain in the ass. When left unchecked it usually leads to a lot of confusion very painfully visible to people around you. This made most of my school life very tormenting. Despite being an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; student, I was always completely lost.
This got better when I found computers. A book I found while sitting in the wrong classroom turned things around for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to terms with ADHD</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 18:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd/</guid>
      <description>After my recent subscription to /r/adhd, I realized how important it can be to share experiences. Even when it is something very personal and seem unlikely that anyone can relate to it, it can be quite helpful for someone who thinks she&amp;rsquo;s alone with her struggles. A while back I deleted most of my old blog posts feeling embarrassed of their suspected cringeworthiness. Now I think it was a mistake. I am thinking about resurrecting them from archive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>