<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trantor on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</title>
    <link>https://channikhabra.com/tags/trantor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in trantor on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 12:37:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://channikhabra.com/tags/trantor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Brands for Software Developers (Talk)</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/personal-brands-for-software-developers-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 12:37:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/personal-brands-for-software-developers-talk/</guid>
      <description>After long diligence, me and my old (Trantor) team decided to organize a meetup to showcase our efforts, and to share our ideas with the local community. The meetup was organized in Trantor on September 18, 2019.
It was a collaborative talk given in 3 parts be me, Ayush Sharma, and Sheenam Narula. Attendance was very low, but that&#39;s usually how it is in Tricity. Overall it was a fun session with lengthy, and mostly fruitful discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and Pretty Docs for Software Projects</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/quick-and-pretty-docs-for-software-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 12:32:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/quick-and-pretty-docs-for-software-projects/</guid>
      <description>I have practiced Readme Driven Development on a number of my projects with varying milage. I have often found myself wishing for a few things:
 More structureWhen writing the documentation, and even more so when reading it. A single markdown file starts getting out of hand really quickly. On my presonal projects I go for org-mode, which keep me satisfied. But when working on a professional gig, it don&#39;t feel right to force other developers into org-mode/emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Software Teams Trantor</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/secure-software-teams-trantor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 16:07:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/secure-software-teams-trantor/</guid>
      <description>I gave this talk in one of internal sessions at Trantor. Goal was to acquaint one of our software teams into the world of application security. This was a basic talk, just to familiarize attendees with basic information security concepts. I leveraged this opportunity to propose setting up a Red Team in Trantor.
As practical part of this session, I created a docker based virtual lab with webgoat set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal brands for software developers</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/personal-brands-for-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 19:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/personal-brands-for-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on the progress we have made in our &amp;ldquo;nurture a culture of individual growth in a software team&amp;rdquo; initiative, I realized there is much to gain from candy wrapping our efforts. As per our plan, we&#39;ll be (and are) giving talks, doing research, and writing itch-scratching code. Coming out of shadows and presenting our efforts in a nice frame present many fold benefits.
My proposal is to invest energy in making our efforts more visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize individual growing in a software team: 2 month progress report</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/maximize-individual-growing-in-a-software-team-2-month-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:08:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/maximize-individual-growing-in-a-software-team-2-month-report/</guid>
      <description>Couple months ago we started an initiative in our team here at Trantor with the focus on nurturing a culture which optimizes personal growth of an individual in the team. I believe it is turning out to be quite successful. We decided we&#39;ll focus on 4 things to achieve our goal:
Interactive sessions of tools/technologies This is where we&#39;ve observed most success. We have had 4 sessions in past 2 months (we do two-week sprints), with following primary topics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to maximize individual growth in a software team?</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/how-to-maximize-individual-growth-in-a-software-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 11:39:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/how-to-maximize-individual-growth-in-a-software-team/</guid>
      <description>Working as a solo freelance developer, I used to have lofty ideas of how a group of people can grow so much more together. I imagined how a mind in the hive can grow at exponential rates. I made several attempts to build communities striving for this, a few were successful to some degree, most were not. Now working in a software development team at Trantor, I am revisiting these ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>