<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal space of Charanjit Singh</title>
    <link>https://channikhabra.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:36:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://channikhabra.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping others to help myself</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-help-others-to-help-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:36:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-help-others-to-help-yourself/</guid>
      <description>It is near impossible for me to get something done if I don&amp;rsquo;t have 100% peaked interest in it at this very moment. Occasionally I can hyper focus on things, but that hyper focus rarely finish things. Hyper focus is like eating all the desert, leaving behind a plate full of broccoli.
I have noticed however that most of the times when I have actually finished something, I was, in my mind, helping someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal brands for software developers</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/personal-brands-for-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 19:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/personal-brands-for-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on the progress we have made in our &amp;ldquo;nurture a culture of individual growth in a software team&amp;rdquo; initiative, I realized there is much to gain from candy wrapping our efforts. As per our plan, we&amp;rsquo;ll be (and are) giving talks, doing research, and writing itch-scratching code. Coming out of shadows and presenting our efforts in a nice frame present many fold benefits.
My proposal is to invest energy in making our efforts more visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize individual growing in a software team: 2 month progress report</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/maximize-individual-growing-in-a-software-team-2-month-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:08:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/maximize-individual-growing-in-a-software-team-2-month-report/</guid>
      <description>Couple months ago we started an initiative in our team here at Trantor with the focus on nurturing a culture which optimizes personal growth of an individual in the team. I believe it is turning out to be quite successful. We decided we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on 4 things to achieve our goal:
Interactive sessions of tools/technologies This is where we&amp;rsquo;ve observed most success. We have had 4 sessions in past 2 months (we do two-week sprints), with following primary topics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to maximize individual growth in a software team?</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/how-to-maximize-individual-growth-in-a-software-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 11:39:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/how-to-maximize-individual-growth-in-a-software-team/</guid>
      <description>Working as a solo freelance developer, I used to have lofty ideas of how a group of people can grow so much more together. I imagined how a mind in the hive can grow at exponential rates. I made several attempts to build communities striving for this, a few were successful to some degree, most were not. Now working in a software development team at Trantor, I am revisiting these ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Chaos : Org mode as a TODO list</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/managing-chaos-org-mode-as-a-todo-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/managing-chaos-org-mode-as-a-todo-list/</guid>
      <description>I am thinking about doing a small series of posts on how I am managing the chaos that I am trying to stop fighting. I hope the chaos of an ADHD mind can be utilized rather than fought against. So far it has been working out pretty great (for past ~8 months). This post is about how I manage my ever exploding list of things I want to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to terms with ADHD - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 13:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd-part-2/</guid>
      <description>One of the important aspects of living with ADHD is getting overwhelmed by thoughts. This is usually a major pain in the ass. When left unchecked it usually leads to a lot of confusion very painfully visible to people around you. This made most of my school life very tormenting. Despite being an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; student, I was always completely lost.
This got better when I found computers. A book I found while sitting in the wrong classroom turned things around for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to terms with ADHD</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 18:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd/</guid>
      <description>After my recent subscription to /r/adhd, I realized how important it can be to share experiences. Even when it is something very personal and seem unlikely that anyone can relate to it, it can be quite helpful for someone who thinks she&amp;rsquo;s alone with her struggles. A while back I deleted most of my old blog posts feeling embarrassed of their suspected cringeworthiness. Now I think it was a mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/relationships/</guid>
      <description>Romantic relationships are such amazing things. I have had moments in my life when I considered myself to have a certain level of control on my mind; in terms of that I can witness myself as an outsider. The introspection, the self awareness that make me think that, very rarely accompany me when I am in a relationship. It seem to have a liking to solitude.
Looking at it from far really brings the picture of a &amp;ldquo;family man&amp;rdquo; home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That sounds fun!</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/that-sounds-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/that-sounds-fun/</guid>
      <description>I got an opportunity to introspect in a conversation with a client when he questioned my use of the word &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo;. What do I mean when I say something is fun? I am not entirely sure. May be when I see something that excites me a little. People have very different interpretations of fun. For me it is usually applying creativity to build something. Activities the involve combination of these two, make me feel most satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 20:29:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I write software to make a living. I enjoy doing so. Both writing software and making a living.
I also enjoy writing, giving talks and discussing engaging topics. Mostly technical. This website has things I am willing to share publicly. You can go through my blog posts, poems, projects, talks, or if you are considering hiring a software architect, then my resume as well.
I believe writing software is a lot more than just churning out code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React/Redux Workshop</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/react-redux-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/react-redux-workshop/</guid>
      <description>React/Redux workshop I gave with Programmers&amp;rsquo; Club Chandigarh meetup group after seeing community&amp;rsquo;s interest in these technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern day JS Apps (2017)</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/modern-day-js-apps-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/modern-day-js-apps-2017/</guid>
      <description>I think this was the second meetup I organized after I came back from Bangalore (to Chandigarh). It was organized with Programmers&amp;rsquo; Club Chandigarh meetup group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some random thoughts</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/some-random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 22:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/some-random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Life can be so overwhelming sometimes. Sometime I wonder how people go on about living without asking questions. Or may be they do ask questions but get satisfied by the answers world has to offer. So much in the world goes around these questions after all. Religions and nations for example. Who’d believe in such farcicality if there were proper answers. Purposelessness is painful. So is loneliness. I seem to have plenty of both of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing to Nothingness</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/losing-to-nothingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 22:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/losing-to-nothingness/</guid>
      <description>Couple weeks back I executed my plan to return to Chandigarh. The plan was to take a break from work and relax for a bit, teach myself some new skills. The real life butted in and I haven’t started the phase 2 yet, but the change was big and I am feeling the affects.
I strive to build bubbles of order in midst of chaos that is life, but what’s still a mystery to me is why change give me a high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React, Redux and Reactive programming</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/react-redux-and-reactive-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/react-redux-and-reactive-programming/</guid>
      <description>Building a React/Redux app with a twist of Reactive programming.
 My first time speaking at a big conference! It was a great experience. There is a video as well!
  Transcript for this talk is available in its Github repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ਚਿਹਰੇ</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poems-chehre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 09:24:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poems-chehre/</guid>
      <description>ਹਸਦੇ, ਖੇਡ੍ਹਦੇ, ਗਿਰਦੇ ਰੋ ਪੈਂਦੇ,
ਮਾਯੂਸੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੁਕਦੇ, ਤੁਰ ਪੈਂਦੇ
ਉੱਚੇ ਉੱਠਦੇ, ਸ਼ੋਰ ਮਚਾਂਦੇ, ਸੁਣਦੇ, ਡਰ ਜਾਂਦੇ,
ਗਿਰਦੇ, ਕੁਰਲਾਂਦੇ, ਭੀੜ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ
ਆਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਗੁੰਮ, ਆਪ ਤੋਂ ਅਣਜਾਣ,
ਬਣਦੇ, ਢਹਿੰਦੇ, ਚੱਲੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ
ਥੱਲੇ ਤੱਕ ਕੇ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦੇ, ਉੱਤੇ ਤੱਕ ਕੇ ਮੁਰਝਾਂਦੇ,
ਭੁੱਲ ਜਾਂਦੇ, ਗੁਮਾਨ ਕਰਦੇ, ਆਪਣਾ ਅਕਸ ਨਾ ਪਛਾਣ ਪਾਂਦੇ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My overplanning nature and how it help me</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/my-overplanning-nature-and-how-it-help-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 22:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/my-overplanning-nature-and-how-it-help-me/</guid>
      <description>Although I try my best to not fall in the conformist’s trap, there is always a force lurking right beneath the conscious which want me to fit in. I remember my obsession for control and planning from quite early childhood. It used to be a major source of frustration; not that I was obsessive about planning things, but that everyone else was not.
Over time I figured it was me who was the odd one; so I subconsciously started suppressing this (over?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt of my rebellion</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/debt-of-my-rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 22:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/debt-of-my-rebellion/</guid>
      <description>Most of my school life I was very confused, depressed perhaps. I was a “good boy”, as they call those traumatized, obedient kids. Confusion started turning into frustration by the end of my 10th standard. It was the “board” class. Nonsensical pressure, corporal punishment and stupid as fuck rules had started turning my depression into anger. So much pressure was put on by that bloody shithole of a school that one of my classmates had a mental breakdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jschannel RxJS workshop Nov 2015</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/jschannel-rxjs-workshop-now-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/jschannel-rxjs-workshop-now-2015/</guid>
      <description>I was very fascinated about Reactive programming, and when we had a shortage of talks in JsChannel, I decided to give a workshop on RxJS.
The code used in this workshop can be found in my Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reality</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 22:21:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/reality/</guid>
      <description>It is one of those rare times I decide to write a blog post without life taking a huge shit on me. Or am I just projecting success for attracting success? Guess bitches. Hope you&amp;rsquo;re all living in reality and not losing yourself in your imaginary fantasy world. Guess what? You&amp;rsquo;re not living in reality. There is no reality to live in.
Reality like God can not be seen, observed, or proven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ਜਾਗਦੀਆਂ ਲਾਸ਼ਾਂ</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-jagdian-lashan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-jagdian-lashan/</guid>
      <description>ਚਿਰ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਖੋਲ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਚੱਲਿਆ ਤਾਂ
ਭੀੜ &amp;lsquo;ਚ ਰੁੜ੍ਹੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਕੁਝ ਚਿਹਰੇ ਮਿਲੇ,
ਖਿਆਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਦੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਹੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ,
ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਹੀ ਕਬਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਠਿਹਰੇ ਮਿਲੇ
-
ਚਿਹਰਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਇੱਕ ਬਜ਼ੁਰਗ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰ ਦਾ
ਉਸਨੂੰ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕੁਝ ਦਿਖ ਹੀ ਨੀ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ,
ਅੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਲਾਲੀ ਵਿਚ ਖਲਾਅ ਸੀ, ਹਨੇਰਾ ਸੀ,
ਬੋਲੀ &amp;lsquo;ਤੇ ਲਗ ਚੁੱਕਾ ਸੀ ਸ਼ਾਯਦ, ਪਰ ਵਿਕ ਹੀ ਨੀ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ
-
ਚਿਹਰਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਇੱਕ ਮੁੱਛ ਫੁੱਟ ਜਿਹੇ ਜਵਾਨ ਦਾ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Don’t Fuck Up the Hackathons</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/please-don-t-fuck-up-the-hackathons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 22:13:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/please-don-t-fuck-up-the-hackathons/</guid>
      <description>I came to Bangalore few months back attracted by its humming tech culture, lots of meetups and even more so, hackathons. I work as a freelancer, I have no other purpose here. And I was not disappointed until recently. Honestly, I don’t even know what definition of word “hackathon” has for Bangalore. I’d quote Paul Graham here, “the city sends you a message”. Bangalore certainly doesn’t give a message of freedom or even innovation, the message I heard when I came here was that of “milk whatever you can”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a System for Making a System for Productivity</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/making-a-system-for-making-a-system-for-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 22:08:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/making-a-system-for-making-a-system-for-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I thought out hard last night and came up with a system that might (or might not) work. But I have to keep trying till I get it right. Here are some main points of my new system:
#1 Commitment Do 8+ hours on day’s priority #1 before you can open any other website/video on the web. On weekdays it should be work that pay my bills, on weekends it can be 2 things, study/side-kick-projects to try new things/or whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mind Full of Chaos</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/a-mind-full-of-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 20:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/a-mind-full-of-chaos/</guid>
      <description>I need to reinvent a system for keeping myself in check. I can’t think of a single thing I haven’t tried in past; pomodoros, gtd, time boxing, what not. They all work for some time, and then stop working. We find flaws in systems pretty quickly; we find cracks, make excused to let us do the easiest thing, the laziest thing.
No matter what system I would adopt next, it all wears off soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteor Js Jschannel Feb 2015</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/talks/meteor-js-jschannel-feb-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/talks/meteor-js-jschannel-feb-2015/</guid>
      <description>First talk I ever gave. I was new to Bangalore and all excited about the whole idea of meetup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ਮਾਯੂਸ ਸਵੇਰ</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-mayoos-saver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-mayoos-saver/</guid>
      <description>ਕਿਉਂ ਉੱਠਾ ਹਾਂ ਅੱਜ ਮੈਂ ਮਾਯੂਸ ਸਵੇਰ ਲਈ,
ਨਮ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਰਛਾਵੇਂ ਮੇਨੂੰ ਖਾ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਾ ਗਏ&amp;hellip;
ਕਿਉਂ ਚੀਸ ਜਿਹੀ ਉੱਠਦੀ ਏ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਮੁੜ ਬੁਲਾਉਣ ਲਈ,
ਤੇਰੇ ਇਸ਼ਕ ਦੇ ਨੁਮਾਇੰਦੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਰਾਹ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਾ ਪਏ।
-
ਸ਼ੋਰ ਜਿਹਾ ਸੁਣਦਾ ਏ ਕਿਉਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਬੁਲਾਉਣ ਦਾ,
ਝਰੋਖਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਚਿਹਰਾ ਦਿਸਦਾ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ&amp;hellip;
ਮੁੱਖ ਉੱਤੇ ਲਾਣ ਲਈ ਹਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਘੜ ਲਏ,
ਦਿਲ ਉੱਤੇ ਲੱਗੇ ਜੋ, ਨਕਾਬ ਵਿਕਦਾ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Things</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/small-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 19:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/small-things/</guid>
      <description>In this post I am talking about the significance of small things in life, some lessons I’ve learned over time, and some random stuff.
 Everyday I go to bed with bigger than life dreams, promising myself tomorrow is the day when I’ll take a giant step to drop all my bad habits and be a better, more productive person forever. A life full of satisfaction is just a night away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stalemate</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/stalemate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 19:38:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/stalemate/</guid>
      <description>I write here mostly only when things aren’t going well in my life. Writing is a good exercise, it clear thoughts. It work better when others give you their opinions. So please be my guest and share your thoughts in comments. After a quite a roller-coaster ride for past 6-7 months, I am finding myself caught up in a stalemate like situation. That’s what I am writing about here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ਕਾਯਨਾਤ</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-kaynat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-kaynat/</guid>
      <description>ਹੁਣ ਪਰਵਾਨਾ ਜਲੇ ਕਿਉਂ ਸ਼ਮਾ ਦੇ ਲਈ,
ਸ਼ਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੁਣ ਓਹ ਲਾਟ ਨਾ ਰਹੀ,
ਬੰਦਗੀ ਕਰੇ ਕਿਉਂ ਕੋਈ ਸੱਚੇ ਰੱਬ ਦੀ,
ਰੱਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਕੋਈ ਸੱਚੀ ਬਾਤ ਨਾ ਰਹੀ&amp;hellip;
-
ਸਮਾਂ ਆਉਣ ਤੇ ਲੇਆਉਂਦੀ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਸੁਨਿਹਰੀ ਸਵੇਰਾ,
ਮਾਂ ਵਰਗੀ ਓਹ ਚਾਨਣੀ ਰਾਤ ਨਾ ਰਹੀ,
ਹੁਣ ਰਾਤਾਂ ਲੰਮੇਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਤੇ ਹਨੇਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ,
ਕਿਸੀ ਦੁਆ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਕਰਾਮਾਤ ਨਾ ਰਹੀ&amp;hellip;
-
ਰੱਬ ਗੁਲਾਮ ਹੋਇਆ ਹਥੀਂ ਕਾਫਰਾਂ ਦੇ,
ਰੱਬ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਦੀ ਮਜਲੂਮ ਦੀ ਹਾਕ਼ ਨਾ ਰਹੀ,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy of the Cubicles</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/energy-of-the-cubicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 19:35:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/energy-of-the-cubicles/</guid>
      <description>In my so far small software development carrier, I have found place of work to have great influence on my focus, mood and hence productivity. The cubicle in title refers to the place of work, rooms or cabins. In this post I discus how I find a new room to pleasant to work in, and how the same room slowly become cancer for my productivity.
 Recently I’ve started caring about productivity, focus and stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Out of Shell</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/ghost-out-of-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 19:33:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/ghost-out-of-shell/</guid>
      <description>In this post are the thoughts running through my head nowadays. Dreams, hopes and fears. I am depicting myself to be the ghost getting out of my shell created by years of social isolation.
 I am going to Bangalore. Jobless and almost empty-handed. But full of hopes, and fears. Hope that it will be the place I imagine. Silicon Valley of India. Of course not as good as SF, may be more like a pirated version of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3K Later</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/3k-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 19:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/3k-later/</guid>
      <description>This post is follow up to my previous unintentional rant about the situation I was in and the tech scene in my city in general. In this post I am writing the things I went through in past 3 months, joys and burns.
 3 K Yes 3 K is 3000 USD. It might not be too much for 3 month time period (for you), but it’s a huge sum if you see from my eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear First World Dev, Have a Look at Your Nightmare. I Am Going to Live It</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/dear-first-world-dev-have-a-look-at-your-nightmare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 19:24:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/dear-first-world-dev-have-a-look-at-your-nightmare/</guid>
      <description>Tech scene in my city (Chandigarh) is daunting. There is super heavy exploitation of new developers and nobody seem to have any problem with it. In this post I am plotting the situation from my view, and sharing the reasons behind my decision of accepting a job where I’ll obviously get exploited.
 For a long time, I’ve been very afraid of doing a job in my locality. First of my concerns have been that it will hinder my growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ਪੱਥਰ</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-pathr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/poem-pathr/</guid>
      <description>ਪੱਥਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਿਹਰ ਵਿਚ, ਇਸ਼ਕ਼ ਦਾ ਵਪਾਰ ਕੀਤਾ,
ਬਖਤ ਅਜ਼ਮਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ,
ਪੱਥਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਖਹਿੰਦਾ ਖਹਿੰਦਾ,
ਪੱਥਰ ਬਣਦਾ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ&amp;hellip;.,
-
ਇੱਕ ਚੰਨ ਚੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਬਿਰਹੋਂ ਦੇ ਸਦਕੇ,
ਇੱਕ ਫੁੱਲ ਜਿਸ ਮਹਿਕ ਖਿਲਾਰੀ,
ਪੱਥਰਾਂ ਲੜ ਲੱਗਾ ਹਾਂ , ਕੁਮਲ਼ਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ,
ਪੱਥਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਖਹਿੰਦਾ ਖਹਿੰਦਾ,
ਪੱਥਰ ਬਣਦਾ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ&amp;hellip;.
-
ਇੱਕ ਨੈਣ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਵਣ ਦੇ ਸਾਨੀ,
ਕੋਈ ਸੁੱਕੀ ਰਾਤ ਨਾ ਮਾਣੀ,
ਯਾਰ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਠੋਕਰ ਮਾਰੇ,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Reason Every Geek Should Blog For</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/one-reason-every-geek-should-blog-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 19:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/one-reason-every-geek-should-blog-for/</guid>
      <description>Right answer is the most obvious one. Learning. Blogging helps a lot when you are obsessed with learning and creating new things.
You learn a lot if you blog responsibly
I started my first blog in 2011 (I run two now). It was first time I got an Internet connection of my own. I was excited and I did some posts about few things I was trying those days. Some people read it, few praised it, it felt nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My notes to help learning Javascript</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/my-notes-to-help-learning-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/my-notes-to-help-learning-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Patience You need to keep it. Don&amp;rsquo;t rush, it&amp;rsquo;s alright if you are not getting it. Specially if you are from Python world. Javascript is to Python like India is to New Zeland, things are not actually as complicated as they appear, you just need to keep little patience.
Coffeescript is your friend Coffeescript helped me learn to think in javascript more than any book. I am not saying that you should use coffeescript, but use it for learning more about javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Eventually Managed to Leverage My Wave</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/i-eventually-managed-to-leverage-my-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/i-eventually-managed-to-leverage-my-wave/</guid>
      <description>The wave I am talking about here is the period of crests and troughs which I have been experiencing for like always. It has always been a very commoving pull-back experience. Lately I have been through a series of change and started looking at things with a different eye. Here’s a list of things helping me the most.
 My life is like riding a wave. When I am on the crest everything is easy, I am super-curious, confident and over-flowing with energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most beautiful tutorial</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/the-most-beautiful-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/the-most-beautiful-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>The most beautiful tutorial I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read, &amp;ldquo;The Emacs-lisp Intro&amp;rdquo;. Run your Emacs and press &amp;lsquo;C-h-i&amp;rsquo;, and select &amp;ldquo; Emacs Lisp Intro&amp;rdquo; to read it. I am a reader, and learner, I read a lot. I used to prefer learning from books, and have a huge collection 70% of which I haven&amp;rsquo;t even ever opened (and 95% I have never completed). Most of my reads are related to programming, new languages, techniques and frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directionless Wandering: Cursed by Dreams</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.com/blog/directionless-wandering-cursed-by-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 19:04:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.com/blog/directionless-wandering-cursed-by-dreams/</guid>
      <description>It has been about five years since I first got my computer. Endless hours I have spent in front of the two dimensional rectangle, the third world. Before I got the machine, most of my time was spent in the world inside my head. My thoughts, feelings, sensations and so many things. I was never at rest. Then I got the machine. I had dreamed of it for like years before I got one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>