<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>introspection on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</title>
    <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/tags/introspection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in introspection on Personal space of Charanjit Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 18:51:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://channikhabra.github.io/tags/introspection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to terms with ADHD</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 18:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/coming-to-terms-with-adhd/</guid>
      <description>After my recent subscription to /r/adhd, I realized how important it can be to share experiences. Even when it is something very personal and seem unlikely that anyone can relate to it, it can be quite helpful for someone who thinks she&amp;rsquo;s alone with her struggles. A while back I deleted most of my old blog posts feeling embarrassed of their suspected cringeworthiness. Now I think it was a mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/relationships/</guid>
      <description>Romantic relationships are such amazing things. I have had moments in my life when I considered myself to have a certain level of control on my mind; in terms of that I can witness myself as an outsider. The introspection, the self awareness that make me think that, very rarely accompany me when I am in a relationship. It seem to have a liking to solitude.
Looking at it from far really brings the picture of a &amp;ldquo;family man&amp;rdquo; home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That sounds fun!</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/that-sounds-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/that-sounds-fun/</guid>
      <description>I got an opportunity to introspect in a conversation with a client when he questioned my use of the word &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo;. What do I mean when I say something is fun? I am not entirely sure. May be when I see something that excites me a little. People have very different interpretations of fun. For me it is usually applying creativity to build something. Activities the involve combination of these two, make me feel most satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some random thoughts</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/some-random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 22:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/some-random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Life can be so overwhelming sometimes. Sometime I wonder how people go on about living without asking questions. Or may be they do ask questions but get satisfied by the answers world has to offer. So much in the world goes around these questions after all. Religions and nations for example. Who’d believe in such farcicality if there were proper answers. Purposelessness is painful. So is loneliness. I seem to have plenty of both of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing to Nothingness</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/losing-to-nothingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 22:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/losing-to-nothingness/</guid>
      <description>Couple weeks back I executed my plan to return to Chandigarh. The plan was to take a break from work and relax for a bit, teach myself some new skills. The real life butted in and I haven’t started the phase 2 yet, but the change was big and I am feeling the affects.
I strive to build bubbles of order in midst of chaos that is life, but what’s still a mystery to me is why change give me a high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My overplanning nature and how it help me</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/my-overplanning-nature-and-how-it-help-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 22:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/my-overplanning-nature-and-how-it-help-me/</guid>
      <description>Although I try my best to not fall in the conformist’s trap, there is always a force lurking right beneath the conscious which want me to fit in. I remember my obsession for control and planning from quite early childhood. It used to be a major source of frustration; not that I was obsessive about planning things, but that everyone else was not.
Over time I figured it was me who was the odd one; so I subconsciously started suppressing this (over?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt of my rebellion</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/debt-of-my-rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 22:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/debt-of-my-rebellion/</guid>
      <description>Most of my school life I was very confused, depressed perhaps. I was a “good boy”, as they call those traumatized, obedient kids. Confusion started turning into frustration by the end of my 10th standard. It was the “board” class. Nonsensical pressure, corporal punishment and stupid as fuck rules had started turning my depression into anger. So much pressure was put on by that bloody shithole of a school that one of my classmates had a mental breakdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directionless Wandering: Cursed by Dreams</title>
      <link>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/directionless-wandering-cursed-by-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 19:04:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://channikhabra.github.io/blog/directionless-wandering-cursed-by-dreams/</guid>
      <description>It has been about five years since I first got my computer. Endless hours I have spent in front of the two dimensional rectangle, the third world. Before I got the machine, most of my time was spent in the world inside my head. My thoughts, feelings, sensations and so many things. I was never at rest. Then I got the machine. I had dreamed of it for like years before I got one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>